Washington Entrepreneurs Project of Strayer College - Independent Business Owners Oral History Project OHP006
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Washington Entrepreneurs Project of Strayer College - Independent Business Owners Oral History Project
1979-1981
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Strayer College
OHP006
3.75 Linear feet
4 Boxes
Scope and Contents
From 1979 - 1981, Strayer College in Washington, D.C., conducted interviews with representatives of independent businesses. The project chronicles D.C. area businesspeople and their families. Topics include the founding and development of the business; family involvement in the business (past, present, and future); evaluation of local government, financial, and trade association services; involvement in civic and charitable activities; loyalty to the Washington area; and self-assessment of interviewees' choice to be an independent business owner. Companies selected were at least 30 years old and owner-operated. The Project's director was Richard Voelkel.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1892 as Strayer's Business College in Baltimore, Maryland, the College was established to teach business skills. A second branch of the College was opened in Washington, D.C. in 1904. In 1969, the college received the accreditation needed to grant four-year Bachelor of Arts degrees and was renamed Strayer College. In 1998, Strayer College was granted university status by the District of Columbia Education Licensure Commission and became Strayer University.
Custodial History
Strayer College conducted these interviews between 1979 and 1981 and transferred the tapes and transcripts to the Library in 1983. There is no Deed of Gift for this collection, however there is a letter stating that the collection was donated.
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews. Series 2: Interviews Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings.
Oral History; Business; Businesspeople
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews.
  - Henry Barrazotto, 1980 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Walter Bell, 1981 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Richard Bergmann, 1981 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anthony P. Bovello, 1979 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Murry T. Donono, 1981 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Morris Gevinson, 1981 September (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Henry Gichner, 1981 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ivan Hall, 1981 August (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Schell S. Hoye, 1981 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Irving Keller (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Milton Kronheim, 1980 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Robert G. McGuire, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sidney Michelson, 1981 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Marion Peake, 1981 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Robert Peck, 1981 August (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Frank Rich, 1980 November-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - John Slattery, 1981 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A. J. Somerville, 1981 August (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Stern, 1981 August (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fred Water, 1981 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - William P. Weschler, 1981 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Margaret Woodson, Nelson Woodson and Clark Vernon, 1981 August (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings.
  - Henry Barrazotto, 1980 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 06-01)
  - Walter Bell, 1981 June (Box 3, Folder 06-02)
  - Richard Bergmann, 1981 May 22 (Box 3, Folder 06-03)
  - Anthony P. Bovello, 1979 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 06-04)
  - Anthony P. Bovello, 1979 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 06-05)
  - Murry T. Donono, 1981 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 06-06)
  - Morris Gevinson, 1981 September (Box 3, Folder 06-07)
  - Henry Gichner, 1981 April 17 (Box 3, Folder 06-08)
  - Henry Gichner, 1981 April 17 (Box 3, Folder 06-09)
  - Ivan Hall, 1981 August (Box 3, Folder 06-10)
  - Schell S. Hoye, 1981 May 29 (Box 3, Folder 06-11)
  - Irving Keller (Box 3, Folder 06-12)
  - Milton Kronheim, 1980 November 11 (Box 3, Folder 06-13)
  - Milton Kronheim, 1980 November 11 (Box 3, Folder 06-14)
  - Robert G. McGuire, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 06-15)
  - Sidney Michelson, 1981 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 06-16)
  - Marion Peake, 1981 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 06-17)
  - Robert Peck, 1981 August (Box 3, Folder 06-18)
  - Robert Peck, 1981 August (Box 4, Folder 06-19)
  - Frank Rich, 1980 November-1981 October (Box 4, Folder 06-20)
  - Frank Rich, 1980 November-1981 October (Box 4, Folder 06-21)
  - Frank Rich, 1980 November-1981 October (Box 4, Folder 06-22)
  - John Slattery, 1981 October 23 (Box 4, Folder 06-23)
  - A. J. Somerville, 1981 August (Box 4, Folder 06-24)
  - Edwin Stern, 1981 August (Box 4, Folder 06-25)
  - Fred Water, 1981 July 16 (Box 4, Folder 06-26)
  - William P. Weschler, 1981 May 19 (Box 4, Folder 06-27)
  - Margaret Woodson, Nelson Woodson and Clark Vernon, 1981 August (Box 4, Folder 06-28)